Now it's time to find the first link in an article.
现在我们来找到文章中的第一个链接
This might be the trickiest part of the program to
这可能是程序内要写的最棘手的一部分
write because I'm not sure exactly how to write it yet.
因为我目前也没有确定该怎么写
A lot of a programmer's time is spent looking for
很多程序员花大量时间
existing solutions either in libraries or in help forums like Stack Overflow.
在各种库或者像 StackOverflow 这样的论坛里寻找现有的结果
The real art of programming though and the real challenge,
但是编程真正的艺术和挑战
is solving new problems like this one.
是解决像现在这样的问题
And the only way to solve unsolved problems is to try.
并且唯一解决问题的方法就是去尝试
I'll start by finding the first link with my browser's developer tools,
我将从浏览器开发工具中链接中找到第一个链接开始
then I'll try to find it again with BeautifulSoup.
之后我会试着再用 BeautifulSoup 寻找一遍
So here's a random article about a Mr.
这儿有个随机找到的文章 是关于
McNeilly and this first link is to the Ireland article.
Mr.McNeilly 它的第一个链接指向介绍 Ireland 的文章
I'll inspect this link with the developer tools.
我先用开发工具检查这个链接
Okay, so the link is in this anchor tag,
好的 这个链接在一个 a herf 标签里面
which is inside this paragraph tag,
这个标签在一个段落标签里
which is inside this div tag.
该段落标签又在一个 div 标签里面
The div tag has the ID "mw- content-text".
这个 div 标签唯一 id 为 mw-content-text
When I highlight this div I can see that it contains
当我选中这个 div 我看到其包括
the article's text but not anything else like Wikipedia's logo or the menus.
文章的文本 但是没有包含 Wikipedia 的标志和菜单
This seems like the right place to search for links,
这看起来像是寻找链接的正确位置
so I'll try to find it again with BeautifulSoup.
然后我将要试着用 BeautifulSoup 再来寻找一遍
Let's switch to a terminal and start the Python interpreter.
我先切换到命令行终端 并且打开 Python 编译器
I'm using the interpreter here so I can try out a lot of things quickly.
我使用编译器 这样以来我能高效率的尝试一些很多东西
I'm pretty sure I'll have to experiment for a while
我很确定我在我能找到如何正确使用
before I can figure out the right way to use BeautifulSoup.
BeautifulSoup 之前 我就得做一个实验
I could also experiment by writing a program and
我还可以写一段实验性的程序
running it over and over again as I make changes to it.
然后每次更动之后运行它来验证它的正确性
I prefer this interactive workflow though.
从我个人来说我更喜欢在交互模式下这种方式
First up, let's import the libraries we need.
首先 先导入我们需要的库
Now let's download the McNeilly article I'm looking at in my browser.
现在 我们先下载在浏览器看到的 McNeilly 的文章
I'll print this HTML to make sure we got the right thing.
我要打印这段 html 来确认我得到的是想要的东西
Good. This looks like the Wikipedia article.
好的 正是我们的 Wikipedia 文章
This text is about Mr. McNeilly.
文本内容是关于 Mr. McNeilly 的
I double checked because if I had made a mistake or if I had downloaded the wrong thing,
我复查了一遍看看自己有没有犯错误或者下错了东西
I want to know that now.
我现在就来确认一下
Not later on when it'd harder to debug the problem.
而不是在调试程序的时候 那时将会更难检查
Now, I'll feed this HTML into BeautifulSoup.
现在 我把 html 传递给 BeautifulSoup
Let's find that mw-content-text div.
先来找到 id 是 mw-content-text 的 div 标签
In order to look up a tag by ID,
为了能根据 id 找到标签
I need to use the find method like this.
我需要这样来使用 find 方法
No errors. This is good.
运行没有错误 很好
Now, I'll look for the first anchor tag,
现在 我要第一个 a herf 标签
inside of the first paragraph tag, inside of this div.
它在这个 div 标签内的第一个段落标签里
I'll press the up arrow in my keyboard to
我在键盘上按上箭头键
bring back the last command I entered so I can chain
这样我就会回到上一个命令 这样我就可以在上一个命令上
more search terms onto the command. Oh, cool.
直接连接更多的命令 完美
This is the link to the Ireland article which is what we wanted.
这就是我们想要的指向 Ireland 文章的链接
I really only want this URL though,
其实我只想要这个 url 链接
not this whole anchor tag.
而不是整个 a herf 标签
I don't remember how to do that though,
我不知道怎么达成这个要求
so I'll check BeautifulSoup's documentation.
所以我来看看 BeautifulSoup 的文档
Oh, this exact situation is in the QuickStart section.
哦 这和快速开始里面提到的情形一模一样
It looks like I can use the get method on a tag as if it was a dictionary
看起来我要在 a herf 标签上就像在 Python 字典上那样使用 get 方法
and I use "href" as the lookup key. Let's try that.
然后再用 href 作为查询的键值 现在来试试
Great! There is our URL now without any extra HTML around it.
真棒 我们的 url 现在已经没有附带多余的 html
At this point we could paste this code snippet into the program and call it a day,
此时我们可以把这段代码粘贴进程序 然后直到某一天用到这段代码
but if we did that we would be bad programmers.
但是这么做的话 我们可不是个好的程序员
Good programmers test their code.
好的程序员会测试他的代码
We know this works for this one particular article but does it work for every article?
我们只知道现在它对于这段特殊的文章是奏效的 怎么确定他对其他文章也奏效呢
Try this code on your own to find out.
自己试试这段代码
I'll put this BeautifulSoup code
我会把这段 BeautifulSoup 代码
below so you can copy and paste it into your own terminal.
放在下面 这样你可以把它粘贴进自己的命令行终端里面